《虎胆龙威2》
嘿 喔 哟 是假警报 等等
Hey! Whoa! Yo! False alarm! Hold it!
没事了 我来了
It's O.K.! I'm here.
我过来了 好了
Here we are! It's all right.
轻轻的放下 好吗?
Set it down nice and easy, huh?
当然 在违章车辆暂扣处
Yeah, sure, at the impound.
下一次要看好交通标志
Next time, read the sign.
不 你不明白
Hey, you don't understand.
看,我只是来这儿接我老婆飞机的.
Look, I'm just here to meet my wife's plane.
你得把这车还给我
You got to let me have this car.
会的,明天 八点到下午四点
Yeah, sure, tomorrow, 8:00 to 4:00.
你付四十元罚金 我们就还你
You pay 40 bucks, we give it back.
别开罚单  别开罚单
Don't write it up. Don't write it up.
朋友,别这样.这是我岳母的车
Come on, man. This is my mother-in-law's car.
她已经因为我不是牙医而对我很反感了.
She's already mad at me 'cause I'm not a dentist.
瞧,我是警察... 洛杉矶警局
Look, I'm a cop...  L.A.P.D.
哦,我在洛杉矶待过 讨厌的地方
Oh, I was in L.A. once. Hated it.
呃,可以理解
Well, I can understand.
我自己也不喜欢那鬼地方
I don't like it much myself
那是个塑料挡泥板! 小心一点
That's a plastic fender up there! Take it easy!
给点面子,怎么样?
Cut me some slack, will you?
我以前是纽约的警察
Look, I used to be a cop in New York City.
我会搬到洛杉矶完全是因为我太太在那儿找了份工作
I only moved to L.A. because my wife took a job there.
拜托.好不好?
Come on. What do you say?
纽约 华盛顿特区 都是民主的核心
New York , Washington, D.C., the heart of democracy.
一首"星条旗永不落"唱不出两家人
One hand washes the other.
拜托! 老兄 这是圣诞啊
Come on, man. It's Christmas.
那就叫圣诞老人另外给你辆车
So ask Santa Claus to give you another car.
圣诞快乐 朋友
Merry Christmas, pal.
都交给你了 默里
It's all yours, Murray.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
是啊 拉里 我知道
Yeah, I know that, Larry.
电话在哪儿?
Where are the telephones?
在那边
Right over there.
多谢
Thank you very much.
莱昂纳德 阿德金斯在一个更温暖的地方给你报导
持续升温的热点新闻…
Leonard Adkins is in a warmer clime with a story that grows hotter by the minute.
瓦维得共和国的艾加龙机场
Security was tight today at Escalan Airport
此刻戒备森严
in the Republic of Valverde
据政府当局称
where government authorities report
被罢免的雷蒙 埃斯波兰萨将军
that deposed General Ramon Esperanza
经此移交并立即引渡前往美国
will be delivered for immediate extradition to the United States.
仅两年前… 埃斯波兰萨将军
Only two years ago, General Esperanza
还领导该国军队
led his country's army
发动了一场打击共党叛乱分子的斗争
in a campaign against Communist insurgents,
斗争背后是美国的金钱及顾问在撑腰
a campaign fought with American money and advisers.
埃斯波兰萨的下台不仅在该国最近的选举中掀起波澜…
Esperanza's fall from power caused ripples not only in his country's recent election,
在美国国内也一样
but closer to home, as well,
有高级国防官员被指控…
when high-ranking Pentagon officials were charged...
违反国会禁令提供武器给埃斯波兰萨
with supplying him with weapons despite the Congressional ban.
但更多证据显示埃斯波兰萨的部队
But mounting evidence that Esperanza's forces
妨碍了邻国的中立
violated the neutrality of neighboring countries
以致于国会停止对其拔款
made Congress withhold funds,
埃斯波兰萨被指控将拨款挪用
funds which Esperanza is accused of replacing
用来从事获得暴利的可卡因走私
by going into the lucrative business of cocaine smuggling.
虽然埃斯波兰萨 今年初就被解除三军总司令的职务
Although Esperanza was removed as Commander In Chief earlier this year,
但引渡他受审的协议 昨天才达成
the agreement to extradite him was only reached yesterday,
据华盛顿消息灵通人士称
and Washington insiders say
协议的达成源于一个电话
it was a phone call that made it happen,
一个来自…
a phone call from a...
好了 好了
All right, all right.
不管你是谁
If I could find a phone,
找到电话我就打给你
I'd call you, whoever you are.
再见
Bye.
借过 谢谢你
Excuse me. Thank you.
我是麦克莱警督
Yeah, this is Lieutenant McClane.
有人刚呼了我?
Somebody there just beep me?
是指我吗?
I'd like to think I'm somebody.
亲爱的 干嘛呢? 在哪儿?
Honey, what are you doing? where are you?
降落了吗?
Did you land yet?
别忘了这是90年代?
It's the nineties, remember?
微芯片 微波炉 传真机 无线电话
Microchips, microwaves, faxes, air phones.
就我而言…
As far as I'm concerned...
冷冻披萨是科技进步的最高峰
progress peaked with frozen pizza.
听着,我们降落大约会迟半个多小时
Listen, we're gonna be about half an hour late landing.
我只是想让你知道
I just wanted to let you know.
孩子们好吗?
The kids OK?
他们正在为你父母给的那些糖喜不自禁呢
They're about to lose their minds from all the sugar your parents are giving them.
你借妈的新车 她有为难你吗?
Did Mom give you a hard time about borrowing her car?
没有 还没呢
No. Not yet.
听我说 亲爱的 等你落了地 我们租一辆车…
Listen, honey, when you land, can we just rent a car...
把孩子交给你父母 我们住旅馆
check into a hotel, leave the kids with your parents?
叫房间服务订瓶香槟如何?
Order some room service, a bottle of champagne? What do you say?
一言为定 警督
You're on, Lieutenant.
那就半小时后见了 我爱你 拜
I'll see you in half an hour, honey. I love you. Bye.
你看科技是不是很奇妙?
Isn't technology wonderful?
- 我老公可不这么想 - 我是这么想
- My husband doesn't think so. - I do.
我以前得带着那种麻烦的催泪瓦斯
I used to carry around those awful Mace things.
但现在…
Now...
哪个杂种惹我我就电他
I zap any bastard that screws with me.
我在我家的狗身上试过
I tried it on my little dog.
可怜的家伙 瘸了一个星期
Poor thing limped for a week.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我看你很眼熟
You look really familiar to me.
很多人都说 我上过电视
I get that a lot. I've been on TV.
没错 我也是
Yeah. Me too.
- 拿一下工具  - 没问题
- Grab the tools. - You got it.
这是艾美 尼可 在艾加龙机场现场报导
This is Amy Nichole, live from Escalan airport,
雷蒙 埃斯波兰萨将军 刚在戒护森严下抵达此处
where deposed general, Ramon Esperanza, has just arrived under heavy guard.
这位被罢黜的独裁者似乎心情愉快
The deposed dictator's mood seems jubilant.
像是竞选候选人一样微笑并向人群挥手
He is smiling and waving to the crowd, like a man running for political office.
...成千上万的政治犯 包括新任总统…
...thousands of political prisoners, including the new president.
毫无疑问,不管在国外还是在这儿,他仍然拥有热情的支持者
There's no doubt he still has some ardent supporters, both here and abroad.
国会谣言满天飞说有…
Rumours abound on Capitol Hill that there were...
- 怎样? - 抱歉打扰你 先生
- Yeah? - Sorry to bother you, sir.
我们正在检查我们的装备
we're checking our equipment.
- 管线有什么问题吗? - 这我就不知道了
- Any problems with the conduit line? - I don't know anything about that.
- 介意让我们看看吗?  - 请便
- Would you mind if we take a look? - Help yourself.
把这个教堂给关了 总不太对劲
It don't seem right somehow, closing down this church.
我知道教区会继续使用它
The parish is gonna keep on using it,
但是它不会跟以前一样了
but it won't be the same.
这么多年了 我一直陪伴着它
Been here a lot of years, and I've been right here with it.
是,我好像有种感觉…
Yeah, I kind of feel like...
有一部份的我正和这教堂一起死去
a piece of me is dying along with this church.
呃, 你说得没错
Well, you're right about that.
走私可卡因和贿赂政府官员
...cocaine smuggling and bribing government officials.
他自然不让这些事曝光
He certainly doesn't show it,
无论他的理念多好
but no matter how high his spirits
他们无法隐瞒的事实是
they can't hide the fact that...
美国的反毒品之战
that America's war on drugs
终于捉到了它第一个犯人
has finally taken its first prisoner.
我是巴圭 俱乐部开放了
This is Buckwheat. The clubhouse is open.
在达拉斯 司法部…
Here at Dulles, the men from the Justice Department
正准备逮捕这个象征美国反可卡因之战敌人的人
wait to handcuff the man who symbolises the enemy in America's fight against cocaine.
这场缉毒战可能打赢了,但整个禁毒战却胜负难料
That battle may be almost won, but the war is still in doubt.
莎曼萨柯曼 WNTW夜间新闻
Samantha Coleman, WNTW, for Night-Time News.
收到 上校 完毕
Roger that, Colonel. Out.
是上校
That was the Colonel.
每个人都准备好了 天气怎样?
Everyone's in position. How's the weather?
整个维珍尼亚海岸都在飘雪
We got flurries all along the Virginia coast.
有暴风雪从东北方来
New storm front coming in from the northeast.
- 上帝真眷顾步兵 - 阿门
- God loves the infantry. - Amen.
去执行你们的任务
Carry out your assignments.
- 对时 15:51 - 对好了
- 15.51. Mark. - Check.
待会见
Later.
再见
Adios.
外面可真冷
It's cold out there, man!
我脚跺了有五分钟了
I stomped my feet for five minutes.
两杯卡布其诺 快一点来
Two cappuccinos. Make it fast.
纯威士忌,谢谢
Scotch straight up, please.
抱歉 警官
Excuse me, officers.
说起来像是有点疯狂
This may sound like a wild-goose chase,
但我好像看见…
but I think I saw...
看见什么?
Saw what?
艾维斯 艾维斯·普莱士利(猫王)
Elvis. Elvis Presley.
该死的观光客 得有法律治治他们
Fucking tourists. Ought to be a law.
不好意思,今晚这儿有很多司法部官员
Excuse me. There's a large number of you from the justice department here this evening.
- 有什么具体事由吗? - 例行公事
- Is there any particular reason for that? - Just routine.
例行公事
Just routine?
- 有意见吗? 先生 - 现在还不行
- Any comment, sir? - Not now.
谢谢你 先生 谢谢
Thank you, sir. Thanks.
嘿 那是史都华上校
That's Colonel Stuart over there.
人员调派上出了问题…
Got a little problem with personnel.
在最后一刻换了人
Last-minute replacement.
- 机场的警戒怎么样? - 就我们来看 简直是儿戏
- How's the security here? - Like we figured... ajoke.
史都华上校 能对我们说几句话吗
Colonel Stuart, could we have a few words?
给你两个字:“我操”
You can have two: "fuck" and "you".
不准拍照 你这左倾婊子
No pictures, you pinko bitch.
真嚣张
Old news.
该死的
Damn it!
借过
Excuse me.
老兄
Hey, man.
- 这是什么? - 你有这扇门的钥匙?
- What is it? - You got a key for this door?
有呀 干嘛?
Yeah. Why?
我要你把这门打开 你说干嘛
Because I want you to open it up, that's why.
- 这附近有值班警察吗? - 有机场警察
- Is there a cop on duty around here? - The airport police.
去找他们来
Go get 'em.
把板手递给我
Hand me the wrench.
还得要加班呢   好主意
Going to work overtime. Good idea.
把那头抓紧
O.K., hold that end.
留神
Watch it, man.
好了 太好了…
All right. Perfect.
成功了
Good to go.
喂  这里是禁区
Hey! It's a restricted area.
怎么了?  不能等搬行李的来吗?
What's the matter? Couldn't wait for a skycap?
我们是在这里工作的
We work here.
把证件拿出来
Let's see some ID.
当然 没问题
Sure. No problem.
老天
Jeez.
干!
Fuck!
这是工作小组吗?
This is a tag team?
- 他进来这里然后亮了一下警徽? - 是,他说把你们的人叫回这边来
- He came in here and flashed a badge? - Yeah. He said to bring you guys back here.
老天
Christ.
笨蛋
Fucker!
不准动
Freeze!
猜得真对 混蛋
Nice guess, asshole.
我是个警察 那才是个坏人
I'm a cop. That was the bad guy.
你的证件呢?
Where's your ID?
正在往克里夫兰的路上
On its way to Cleveland?
你什么也不解释…
You did not explain anything.
就把我塞进这个破车里
You just shoved me back here into this cattle car.
- 先生,我们已经告知你机票超卖了 - 这个我可以接受
- Sir, you were told we were overbooked. - Fine. I accept that.
那为什么不给我吃头等舱的餐 我已经花了钱
But why can't I get the first-class meal my network paid for?
- 你知道我是谁? - 我们都看过你的节目
- Do you know who I am? - Yes. We've seen your programme.
你那集“飞行垃圾场”客观反映了空中交通的安全问题
Your episode "Flying Junkyards" was an objective look at air-traffic safety.
不过比起“空中辣妹”那集的教育意义就差远了,不是吗? 小姐
It wasn't nearly as edifying as "Bimbos of the Sky", was it, Connie?
你们认为自己很幽默
You think you're funny.
没关系 我记住了你的工号
Fine. I've got your number.
而我也记住了你的. 坐下吧 先生
And I've got yours. So park it, sir.
好吧
Fine.
- 空中小姐 - 索伯先生
- Stewardess. - Mr Thornberg.
你不能独占我的时间
You cannot monopolise my time.
- 我不能靠这个女人坐 - 什么?
- You cannot put me near that woman. - Excuse me?
他向法院对我提出限制令
He means he's filed a restraining order against me.
我不得靠近他超过五十尺
I'm not allowed within 50 feet of him.
是五十码 把我放在这一区 违背了法庭禁令
50 yards. So by keeping me in this section, you are violating a court order.
我可以告你和这家航空公司
I can sue you and this airline.
这女人在大庭广众打我 羞辱我
That woman assaulted me, and she humiliated me in public.
你做了什么?
What did you do?
打掉了他的两颗牙齿
Knocked out two of his teeth.
你要来杯香槟吗?
Would you like some champagne?
抱歉 麦克莱警官 我得查清楚
Sorry, Officer McClane. I had to check.
这是你的枪和你的警徽
Here's your piece and shield back.
谢啦
Thanks.
在这边 警官
Over here, Officer!
我们了解刚才有枪战
We understand that there was a shooting.
美国司法部官员在场...
The presence of Justice Department officials...
老天
Jesus! Christ!
嘿,就一句,怎么样?
Hey, come on. Just a word, O.K.?
你们他妈这帮人在… 你在这儿干什么?
What the fuck are you people... What are you doing here, man?
这是犯罪现场 你应该把这地方封闭起来
This is a crime scene. You gotta seal this area off.
- 这得由警监决定 - 那你最好带我去见警监,嗯?
- That's up to the captain. - Maybe you better take me up to the captain, then, huh?
柯可兰呢?
Where's Cochrane?
他挂了
He didn't make it.
你来晚了
You're late.
我们遇到麻烦了 上校
We ran into trouble, Colonel.
有个警察 他杀了柯可兰
Some cop... killed Cochrane.
我差点没逃出来,长官
I barely got away, sir.
你的任务呢?
Did you accomplish your mission?
完成了 长官 可是柯可兰…
Yes, sir, but... Cochrane, sir.
嗯,那就没什么大损失
Well, then the damage is minimal.
但处罚可能是严厉的
The penalty could be severe.
你再失误一次…
You fail me again,
就不是空枪了
and the chamber won't be empty.
解散
Dismissed.
小姐…我找不到我的狗
Miss. Miss. I can't find my dog.
小姐 我的狗. 太太 请稍等
Miss. My dog. One minute, ma'am.
请你把这张表填上
I want you to fill out this form.
是谁? 进来
Who is it? Come in.
罗伦佐队长?
Captain Lorenzo?
没错
Yeah.
我是约翰麦克莱
I'm John McClane...
我知道你是谁
Yeah, yeah. I know who you are.
你就是那个违反了7条联邦航空局...
You're the asshole that just broke seven FAA
和5条特区法规在我机场到处跑的混蛋
and five District of Columbia regulations running around my airport
而且还到处乱开枪
with a gun, shooting at people.
你怎么解释你的所作所为?
What do you call that shit?
正当...防卫
Self...defense.
什么,你以为那个洛杉矶警徽…
Well, what, you think that L.A. badge is going to get you
能让你在这儿吃到免费午餐吗?
a free lunch or something around here?
不是 或许该受到身为专家的礼遇
Well... maybe a little professional courtesy.
在一个圣诞节的机场里?
Huh! In an airport on Christmas week?
你在开玩笑
You've got to be kidding.
别管礼遇了
O.K. Fuck courtesy.
你的专业精神呢?
How about just being professional?
你手下自犯罪现场走开 警长
Your boys just walked away from a crime scene, Captain.
你没把那地方给围起来
You can't wrap this thing up in 10 minutes.
你一定得把那地带封闭 照相片
You got to seal the area off, dust for prints...
别对我说教
Hey, don't lecture me, hotshot.
我知道我是在干么 我们会去采指纹
I know what I'm doing. We're going to dust it down.
照相 采样
We'll take all the pictures. We'll sweep for fibers.
什么时候去? 等三四百人去过后
When will you do this? After 400 people go through?
要是采到指纹 你才狗运呢!
You'd be lucky to get a print from one of your people.
- 把那个地区关闭… - 把那个地区关闭?
- Shut down that area... - Oh, shut the area down.
就那么简单 把它关闭?
It's that simple, huh? Just shut the area down?
干! 我什么人都有
Shit,Yeah, and I got everybody from the Shriners' convention
有兄弟会的 也有童子军
to the goddamn Boy Scouts in here!
我有失踪的儿童 失踪的狗
I got lost kids, lost dogs...
等一下
Not now! Later!
我还有国际外交官
I got international diplomats.
我还有从可爱动物园来的驯鹿
I got a fucking reindeer flying in here from the fucking petting zoo!
但 约翰麦克莱 他有个小问题
But John McClane, he's got a little problem.
咱们把整个机场关闭
Let's shut down the whole fucking airport!
要是我这么说上头的人会怎么说
What do you think they'll say upstairs when I tell them that?
拿起电话来请示呀!
Phone and find out.
用不着鉴识科的笨蛋来告诉我这只是一个小贼想偷行李
I don't need fucking forensics to tell me this was some punk stealing luggage!
行李? 这小贼用的枪是GLOCK-7 你知道吗?
Luggage? That punk pulled a Glock 7 on me. You know ?
是德国制陶瓷枪
That's a porcelain gun made in Germany.
X光机看不出来的
It doesn't show up on airport x-ray machines
它的价值超过你一个月的所得
and costs more than you make in a month.
我挣多少你一定会吃惊的
You'd be surprised what I make in a month.
比一块九毛八还多?
If it's more than $1.98...
别去相信报上对你的报导
Hey, McClane, don't start believing your own press, huh?
没错 我知道你的一切 还有在洛杉矶中臣大厦那件事
Yeah, I know all about you and that Nakatomi thing in LA.
但电视说你是个人物并不表示你就是
But just cos the TV thinks you're hot shit, that don't make it so.
看,你现在是在我这个小池子里
Look, you are in my little pond now,
而我是管这池子的大鱼
and I am the big fish that runs it.
所以你杀了条不值钱的人命
So you capped some lowlife.
没关系
Fine.
我会给你他妈的洛杉矶警监寄封表扬信的
I'll send your fucking captain in LA a fucking commendation!
现在滚你的吧!
Now, get the hell out of my office
省得我必须把你赶出机场去
before I have you thrown out of my goddamn airport!
嘿,我问你一件事 卡敏
Hey, Carmine, let me ask you something.
是什么最先启动金属侦测器?
What sets off the metal detectors first?
是你屁眼里的子弹还是你大脑里的大粪?
The lead in your ass or the shit in your brains?
肥猪!
Fat fuck.
这家伙身上有身份证明吗?
Any ID on this guy?
那个让别人去操心吧!
That's somebody else's problem.
你的车预备好了 就在这签字
Your car's ready. Sign right here.
我要借用这个和这个 马上还回来
I need to borrow this and this. I'll bring it right back.
嘿
Hey!
嘿,喂,等一下
Hey! Yo! Hold up!
喂
Yo!
等一下
Hold up, boys.
等一下 我们要查一件事
Hold up. We got to check something.
- 你在什么? - 讨人厌的差事
- What are you doing? - Pretty gruesome fucking job.
一团乱 忘了采这混蛋的指纹了
All the confusion in there, forgot to get this clown's prints.
老天
Ew! Christ.
你该在殓房做的
You're supposed to do that at the morgue.
现在不是了,航空署对送达后已死的有新的操作流程
Not anymore. Got a new SOP for DOAs from the FAA.
我看这个人是活不了了
I don't think this one's going to make it.
多谢
Thanks a lot.
护航机开走了
没关系 现在没危险
咱们一路到美国都会平安的
要飞多久?
3个半小时
戴着这链子好痛
能把这个拿掉吗? 小鬼
你想我还能往哪儿跑呢?
抱歉 将军 我不能这么做
很好 小鬼 很好
你是个好兵
好吧 不给我自由 给我借个火总行吧?
我是波威尔
Powell here.
把你嘴里的海绵蛋糕拿出来
Take that Twinkie out of your mouth
拿起铅笔 行吗?
and grab a pencil, will ya?
哈哈! 约翰 你好吗?
Ha ha! Hey,John, how are you doing?
荷莉放了我一天鸽子 我孤身一人呆在华盛顿
Holly stood me up a day, and I'm here alone in D.C.
和我岳父母
with my in-laws.
岳父母...啊?
Eh, the old in-laws, huh?
他们很喜欢自己的警察女婿吧?
They do love their policemen son-in-laws.
听着 艾尔
Listen, Al,
局里的传真机什么号码?
what is the fax machine telephone number there at the station?
呃
Uh...
555-3212
555-3212.
3212 等一下
3212. Hold on a second, all right?
我要传点东西给你
I want to send you something.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你会用传真机? 这可是破天荒
You and faxes? This is a first.
是的,呃,荷莉告诉我...
Yeah, well, Holly told me...
我该跟上90年代潮流
I should wake up and smell the nineties.
这样?
This way?
不对 该这样
No. That way.
上下颠倒了
Wait. It's upside down.
没有关系
It doesn't matter.
行了 送进机器了
O.K. Here it comes.
正在传送
I'm sending you something right now.
等一下 牛仔
Hold on a second, cowboy.
是指纹?
Fingerprints?
这里有具无名尸体
We've got an unidentified stiff here.
我用笔圈起了
I've circled the whirls in pen
以防传送后模糊
in case the transmission's a little fuzzy.
听着 把它抄送给州、联邦和国际刑警
Listen, run it through state and federal, and if you can, run it through Interpol.
好的 这是怎么一回事?
Will do. Well, what's this about?
哦,只是第六感
Oh,just a feeling I have.
哎呀,一旦你有第六感
Ouch. When you get those feelings,
保险公司准破产
insurance companies start to go bankrupt.
听我说 这里的传真机号码是…
Listen, the, uh, fax number is...
在传过去的纸上头有
Is on the top edge of the transmission...
就在你刚收到的纸上头有
Is on the top edge of the transmission you just got.
哦,一个飞机场?
Oh, an airport, huh?
你没在别人的池子里撒尿吧?
Listen, you're not pissing in somebody's pool, are you?
没错 而且我没带漂白粉
Ha ha. Yeah. And I'm fresh out of chlorine.
今天的风暴正要开始减弱…
Just as this storm starts breaking,
气象卫星又送坏消息来了
the satellite will feed up and drop the other shoe.
前头那个峰面
Look at this new front moving in.
和这个比真是小巫见大巫
Makes its baby brother look like chicken shit.
我可以在跑道上撒沙子
Well, I can sand down all the runways
并且在飞机降落间隙里整好
and keep the plows going between landings,
可是你得给我时间来干活儿
but you got to downshift them up there, give me time to work.
没问题
You got it.
好吧 各位…
All right, everyone.
让飞机降落放慢一些…
Let's call all our birds and slow them down
这样咱们才能清理停机坪
before we get a parking lot over our heads.
从密西西比的飞机
The line starts at the Mississippi,
开始排队降落
and they better start taking numbers.
还要再来一杯吗?
Can I get you another?
不了 谢谢
No, thank you.
再过15到20分钟
I only have to look at his face
我就不用再对着他那张脸了
for another 15 or 20 minutes.
女士们 先生们 我是机长
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the captain speaking.
我刚接到达拉斯航管中心通知
I've just been informed by Dulles Traffic Control
前方有一个锋面向我们靠近
that there's a weather front moving in ahead of us.
也许咱们得在天上多待一会儿了
We may be up here a little while longer.
谢谢
Thank you.
我又重新想了想…
On second thought...
艾尔
Al?
我在 搭档
Hey, I'm right here, partner.
现在你那尸体的档案正传送过来
Your stiff's dossier is coming through right now.
内容是什么?
What can you tell me about him?
他死了
He's dead.
这个还需要电脑告诉你?
You needed a computer to figure that one out?
不 不是 你没明白我的意思
No, no. You don't follow me.
据国防部说
According to the Department of Defense,
他已经死了两年了
he's been dead for two years.
什么?
What?
没错 奥斯华·科奇蓝中士
That's right. Sergeant Oswald Cochrane.
美国派驻洪都拉斯的军事顾问
American adviser in Honduras.
死于1988年5月11日 直升机意外
Killed in a helicopter accident 5...11...88.
警官
Officer.
看样子里面大有文章
Read between the lines, and I'd say it looks like a lot of black...bag stuff to me.
我明白了
Yeah, I see it.
行了 谢啦!
All right, Al. Thanks a lot.
随时效劳
Hey, anytime.
好的
O.K.
嗨 我还有不到1小时就可以休息…
Say, I close in about an hour.
要不要去喝一杯?
Maybe we can go get a drink?
只是传个真 女士
Just the fax, ma'am.
只是传个真
Just the fax.
等等 我瞧见了一个人
Hey, wait a second. Wait. I see somebody.
我会再打给你的
I'll call you back.
去年圣诞节的鬼魂
The Ghost of Christmas Past.
中臣大厦? 洛杉矶? 你是约翰·麦克莱 对吗?
Nakatomi? L.A.? You're John McClane, right?
你是谁?
Who are you?
萨姆·坷曼 WNTW电视台的
Sam Coleman. WNTW news.
失陪了
Excuse me.
帮我个忙 我瞧见那具尸体了
Give me a break. I saw the stiff.
听说是你的杰作
Word is that was your handiwork.
不是 我只会做针线活
No. I only do needlepoint.
太棒了 国际机场刚关闭了
Great. National just shut down.
全都是冰
Totally iced.
他们叫飞机都飞到咱们这儿来
They're going to be sending us their planes.
假日快乐
Happy, happy holiday.
特鲁多先生,最糟的是那帮媒体…
The worst part, Mr. Trudeau, was the press.
哦,他们无孔不入,到处打探埃斯波兰萨的消息
Oh, they were here anyways, crawling all over the Esperanza story,
已经有新闻报导了
so they got it right on the fucking news.
真是血迹斑斑
You know, bloodstains and all.
我真想把所有记者
Personally, I'd like to lock every damn reporter
都挡在机场外头
out of the airport, but then they'd just pull
但是他们会大嚷新闻自由
that freedom...of...speech crap on us.
然后美国平民自由协会就会朝我们泼屎
Then the ACLU would be all over us.
电视上的谋杀报导
Murder on television.
真给圣诞节开了个好头
Hell of a start for Christmas weekend.
这次又是怎么回事? 跟上次一样的黑帮活动?
What is it? A gang thing like last time?
除非你说的黑帮是在布拉格堡训练的
Only if your gangs get their training at Fort Bragg.
见鬼 这人是谁?
Who the hell is this?
麦克莱
Uh...uh, McClane.
我是个警官
I'm a police officer.
乱闯禁区的警官
In an unauthorized area.
洛杉矶来的 特鲁多先生 那有个屁用
L.A., Mr. Trudeau, don't mean shit.
我上次验胆固醇的时候也这么说
That's what I said about my last cholesterol test.
那你的问题是什么? 麦克莱警督
So what's your problem, Lieutenant McClane?
我确信罗伦佐警监已经向你解释过了
I'm sure Captain Lorenzo has explained to you
我们关于小贼的小小争议
the minor little fracas with the minor little thieves.
也许他能再解释一下这个
Maybe he can explain this.
（机密任务:特殊训练死于...）
（5-11-88直升机坠毁）
所有的系统都接通了 上校
All systems tapped, Colonel.
启动吧!
Fire it up.
5分钟后行动
" H" minus five minutes.
准备好
Stand by.
咱们在殓房有一具
All right. We've got a body in the morgue
死了两次的尸体
that seems to have died twice.
假设不是电脑出错
Assuming it's not a computer error,
咱们该假设什么?
what do we assume?
有人想对机场图谋不轨
That somebody's about to seriously fuck with this airport.
为什么这么说?
What is that supposed to mean?
我知道我们这里都是笨蛋,麦克莱
I mean, I know we're dummies up here, McClane,
所以告诉我们你天才的想法
so give us a taste of your genius.
你说的是劫机? 抢劫? 还是别的什么?
This a hijacking? A robbery? What?
我不能确定
Look, I'm not sure.
哦 他不能确定 我太震惊了
Oh, he's not sure. Well, I'm stunned.
我得去躺一会儿了
I got to lie down.
能做到这个程度的只有行家
The only people that go to this much trouble are professionals...
不是偷行李的小毛贼也不是小混混
not luggage thieves and not punks.
哪方面的行家?
Professional at what?
你他妈到底认为是什么? 嗯!
What the fuck do you think this is, huh,
巡逻保安?
the safety patrol here?
这可是一份职业雇佣兵的履历…
This is the resume of a professional mercenary.
还有一个世界上最大的毒贩正往这儿赶
You got the world's biggest drug dealer on his way here.
你是需要一把计算尺才算得出来
You need a slide rule to figure this out,
还是需要在你开始提问前在尸袋里再来上具尸体?
or maybe another body in a zipper bag before you start asking questions?
那该死的尸体是你给我们弄来的
You're the one that gave us that fucking body.
别忘了
Remember that.
是,我没忘
Yeah, I remember that.
罗伦佐 现在叫你所有轮班的部下来报告
Lorenzo, have all your shift commanders report in. Now.
什么? 你相信他的话?
What? You're not buying into this?
我要他们报告一切不同寻常的事…
I want them to report anything out of the ordinary,
不管是多小的事 明白吗?
no matter how trivial. You got that?
照办
Yeah, I got it.
我的天呀!
Oh, my God!
怎么了?
What?
跑道 你瞧!
The runways.
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
照明统统给关掉了
They're shutting down.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
立刻把紧急照明打开
Go to emergency lighting now.
紧急状况 我们现在处于黄色警报状态
Emergency. We are in a code yellow.
后备系统失灵了
Backup systems won't come up.
换到另一个终端试试看
Shunt to another terminal.
巴比 你那边怎样?
Bobby, what do you got?
完了. 整个线路都不管用了
Nothing. The whole network is down.
或许咱们该打电话给电力公司?
Maybe we should call the power company, huh?
他们跟我们在同一个该死的供电区
We're on the same goddamn grid. We're hot.
达拉斯机场 怎么回事? 我正要进场
Dulles, what's going on? I'm on approach.
保持现在位置.
Maintain position. Repeat.
下面怎么了?
What's going on down there?
收到 我们正在处理
Roger. We're on it.
现在不行 推迟降落
We're unable right now. Please delay.
富士604 错过了进场程序
Fuji 604. Execute published missed...
请重新来过
approach procedure and hold.
TWA23 你还不能进场
TWA 23, unable to clear you for approach at this time.
请爬高 保持1万尺高度
Climb to and maintain one zero thousand.
检查所有系统 不会有这种事的
I've checked all systems. It ain't happening.
问题出在哪儿?
What's it look like?
进场雷达失效了…
Approach control... it's gone.
老天 自动导航系统失效了
Jesus. Instrument landing system is down.
确定 自动导航系统失效了
Confirmed. ILS is dead.
所有系统都完蛋了
Every goddamn system's dead.
空中防撞警告系统失效了
And Inmac monitors are down.
注意 所有导航员 请注意
Attention all controllers. Attention.
红色警报
We have a code...red alert.
所有在我们塔台管制区的…
Every aircraft approaching our sector
尚未进入着陆航线的飞机…
who are not already in our landing pattern
立即安排转往附近机场
gets diverted to their alternate airport now.
己进入着陆航线的所有飞机…
Everyone already on approach
或是正要进场的飞机
or inside our pattern
维持在外指点标的高度
holds at the outer markers.
让他们放慢 别紧张 排队来
Stack 'em, pack 'em, and rack 'em.
快
Move.
快找人来帮忙
Get someone on it!
这里发生的事千万别泄露出去
All right. Not a word of this leaves this room.
这机场有一万五千人
There must be 15,000 people in this airport,
我们可不希望发生恐慌
and we don't need panic on our hands.
我们也许刚争取到了两个小时
We just bought ourselves maybe two hours.
两小时后 燃料用完的飞机
After that, those planes low on fuel
就不能兜圈子了
aren't going to be circling.
他们会掉在白宫草地上的
They're going to be dropping on the White House lawn.
麦克莱 这就是你担心的?
McClane, this what you expected?
不
No.
这只不过是开始!
This is just the beginning.
航空署热线!
FAA hot line.
他们怎么会知道的?
How could they know already?
不可能知道
They can't.
也许是那些把你插头拔掉的人打来的
Maybe it's the boys that pulled all your plugs.
接到扬声器去
Put it on speaker.
注意 达拉斯机场指挥塔 注意
Attention, Dulles Tower. Attention.
有人说盲人听力格外好
They say that blind men become very attentive by way of compensation.
既然现在你们又盲又聋…
Now that you're both blind and deaf,
我想我已经集中起你们的注意力了
I think I've got your attention.
我知道你们在录音
I'm aware your recorders are active,
所以我长话短说
so I'll be quick.
过一会儿你们可以再听重播
You can play me back later to your heart's content.
你怎么会用这条线的? 你是谁?
How did you get on this line? Who is this?
我是谁并不重要
Who I am is unimportant.
重要的是我要什么
What I want...
如果你不想让那些飞机油料用光
Well, if you don't want those planes to start splashing into the Potomac
掉进波托马克河的话
as they run out of fuel,
我要什么就很重要
what I want is very important.
58分钟后有架飞机会在这机场降落
Aplane will be landing at this airport in 58 minutes.
它是FMI外籍军机一号
It is FM...1, Foreign Military One.
我确信你们都知道…
Now, I'm sure you gentlemen are well aware of the unique nature...
埃斯波兰萨?
Esperanza?
飞机上乘客的重要性
of this flight, the importance of its cargo.
任何人均不得接近那架飞机
This plane will not be met by anyone.
它将降落在我指定的跑道上
It will land on a runway of my designation,
不许任何人去接近它
where it will remain isolated and unapproached.
我想我已经解释清楚了我对那架飞机的关注
That will conclude my interest in this aircraft
以及你们对那架飞机的责任
and your responsibility for it.
同时
At the same time,
我要一架加满油的747改装货机
I want a 747 cargo conversion fully fueled
随时听我指挥
and placed at my disposal.
给你们2分钟时间 通知待进场飞机
You have two more minutes to advise your inbound aircraft
保持他们的方位
to hold at their outer radio marker.
然后你们就只能接收 不能发声了
After that,you will be able to receive only.
想修复系统的任何企图…
Any attempt to restore your systems
都会遭到严厉的惩罚
will be met by severe penalties.
他在虚张声势
He's bluffing.
该死的,你不能这么做
Damn it, you can't do this.
我正在这么做
I am doing this.
大家听好
O.K., you guys, listen up.
我要你启动15号计划
I need you to punch up a code 15.
我有个主意 我需要你帮忙…
I got an idea, and I need your help.
要是埃斯波兰萨上了那架飞机
If Esperanza gets on that plane
飞到一个跟咱们没引渡条约的国家
and makes it to a country with no extradition treaties,
我们就完了
we're fucked.
他们用咱们的系统通话
They're talking to us on our own system.
他们一定离得很近
They got to be close.
我会叫我的手下把这里搜个底朝天
I'll have my men tear this airport apart.
就在这么一丁点儿时间之内?
Just in the nick of time, huh?
嘿 麦克莱 我这里有一级战术小分队
Hey, McClane, I got a first...class unit here,
SWAT特警队等等
S.W.A.T. team and all.
我们可不需要事后诸葛亮
We don't need any Monday...morning quarterbacks.
我太太在其中一架飞机上
My wife's on one of the goddamn planes these guys are fucking with.
所以我才投身其中
That puts me on the playing field.
如果你在我告诉你时就行动
If you'd have moved your fat ass when I told you to,
我们也不会像现在这么糟了
we wouldn't be hip deep in shit right now.
就这样吧. 保安 你离开这里
That's it. Security. You're out of here.
特鲁多先生 需要我提醒你
Mr. Trudeau, do I have to remind you
有关 航空局
about FAA regulations
不准闲人
regarding unauthorized personnel
进指挥塔的规定吗?
in the control tower?
我们只需找到发讯的方法
All we have to do is find a way to transmit.
是啊,好. 谁跑一趟五金行买一台发报机?
Yeah, right. Somebody want to run down to Radio Shack and get a transmitter?
我们有一台
We already have one.
在新的航站大厦里
The new terminal wing they're building...
二十条航线都有自己的后备电脑
20 airlines when it's done, all with their own reservation computers,
依照天线排列的
all tied in to a nice big antenna arrangement.
带麦克莱先生出去 请他出去
You'd better see Mr. McClane out.
这里没有你的事
You got no business being up here.
我告诉你们.全部都齐备了
I'm telling you guys. Everything we need is over
只需要接上附属空中通道
by the Annex Skywalk just sitting there,
就可以使用
waiting to go on line.
附属空中通道?
The Annex Skywalk?
你要对付的是行家
You're dealing with pros here.
你是骗不了这些人的 听我说
You can't fuck with these people.
萨姆·坷曼 WNTW电视台
Sam Coleman. WNTW news.
特鲁多先生, 今天这里谣言四起
Mr. Trudeau, there are a lot of rumors flying around here today.
不 不行 女士
No way. No way, lady.
见鬼 不 不
Hell, no. No.
太过份了 柯曼
This is off limits, Coleman.
请出去
Get them out of here.
你想到的一切 他们也都会想到
Anything you can think of, they'll think of, too!
把你他妈的手拿开
Get your fucking hands off me.
该死的  把他们二个赶出去
For shit's sake. Just get them both out of here.
大厅警卫 回答
Lobby Security, come in.
我是汤姆逊
Tomalson here.
我是罗伦佐警监
This is Captain Lorenzo here
以及两个未授权入内人员在这该死的指挥塔里
with two unauthorized personnel in the fucking tower.
别他妈在那里发呆…
Now, would you get your thumb out of your ass,
把他们赶出电梯去
get them out of the elevator,
不然你就等着在你的圣诞祙子里找到解雇信吧
or you're going to find a goddamn pink slip in your Christmas stocking.
知道了 我们走
10...4. Let's go.
该死的
Goddamn!
谁想起什么要说的?
Anything who can think of?
不能弄那个家伙?
Can't fuck with what guy?
他妈的 抓紧
Shit. Hang on over there.
抓紧就对了
Just hang on.
大毒贩正被送往监狱
Big drug dealer on his way to prison,
机场又发生枪战
gunfight at airport,
咖啡厅里所有航管员都被呼叫并迅速离开
every controller in the coffee shop getting beeped and hauling ass,
你又在里头搅和
and you rocking the boat.
有关连吗?  拜托 麦克莱
Connection? Come on, McClane.
就说两句
Just a few words.
OK,就两句. 滚蛋
O.K.,just a few words. Fuck off.
谢了 史都华上校 已经对我说了
Thanks, but I already got that from Colonel Stuart.
史都华
Stuart.
被国会炒鱿鱼的那家伙. 就是他
The guy that got canned by Congress. That's who he was.
谁? 他是谁? 什么? 嘿!
Huh? Who he who? What? Hey!
嘘 没关系 这个我以前干过
Shh! It's O.K. I've done this before.
嗨
Hi.
还有一个到哪里去了?
Where's the other one?
我猜他有幽闭恐怖症
Claustrophobic, I guess.
这是特高频系统, 但飞机离得这么近
It's a VHF system, but the planes are so close
没关系
it doesn't matter.
我可以在三十分内架设完毕
I can rig our frequency in 30 minutes,
然后做无线电交联就行了
wire in a crossover, and we're hot.
即使这些飞机也分不出哪里不同
Even the planes wouldn't know the difference.
找到你需要的设备 不管你去借、去偷、去杀
Get what you need. Borrow. Steal. Kill.
我要SWAT队跟他去掩护他
I want my S.W.A.T. team to go with him as cover.
我们能想到的 他们都能想到
Whatever we can think of, they can think of, too.
哦,不.我他妈简直不敢相信.
Oh, man. I can't fucking believe this.
另一个地下室 另一个电梯
Another basement. Another elevator.
相同的鬼事发生在我身上两次
How can the same shit happen to the same guy twice?
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是马文
I'm Marvin.
马文  我是马文
Marvin. I'm Marvin.
我以为你要...
I thought you was trying...
偷唱片 仅此而已
to steal my records, that's all.
我只是个看门的
I'm just the janitor.
这是达拉斯塔台 呼叫所有
This is Dulles Approach to all aircraft
因暴风雪滞飞的飞机
holding at Potomac Vortex.
我们发生了技术问题
We are experiencing some technical problems here.
气候正不断在恶化
Weather conditions, which have been deteriorating all day,
人为失误使得情形更加复杂
have now been complicated by an unforeseen human factor.
这个事故影响了 我们所有的电子设备
This has affected all of our electronic equipment
以及备用系统
and their redundant backups, as well.
现在 导航和进场系统已经失效
As a result, our Nav and approach systems are down,
一分钟后 我们就无法 再发出无线电通讯
and we expect to lose voice in another minute.
我要你们 继续
We want you to continue...
按先前指令保持在外指点标高度
holding at the outer marker as directed
并等待进一步之指示
and wait for further instructions.
一旦我们的系统重新连线
As soon as we're back on line,
我们将按你们的存油量加速安排降落
we'll expedite your landings on a fuel...emergency basis.
祝各位好运
Good luck.
上帝保佑
God bless.
好了 把时间表改掉
All right. Change the boards.
(延迟)
嘿,退后
Hey, stand back.
空中附属通道?
The Skywalk Annex.
不,妈的,是附属空中通道
No, Goddamn it. The Annex Skywalk.
这是他们赶我出来之前听到最后一句话
It's the last thing I heard before they kicked me out.
来看看这里
Well, let me see here, now.
一定是这个 就在这里
Well, this must be it right there.
看到吗? 那是个架高的平台
See? That's the raised platform,
新航站大楼在这
and there's the new terminal.
这是你的空中通道
There's your Skywalk.
该死的隘路
Goddamn bottleneck.
是个伏击的好地方
Nice place for an ambush.
怎么样到那里最快?
What's the fastest way
你能把我从那弄出来吗？
you can get me out to that spot?
这可不是我份内的工作
This kind of thing wasn't in my job description.
别操心 巴恩先生 我们会保护你
Don't worry, Mr. Barnes. We'll watch your back.
是吗? 那谁保护你们?
Yeah? Who watches yours?
主通风管道
Main ventilation duct.
中奖了
And bingo.
就只这一回我想过一个普通的
Just once, I'd like a regular,
正常的圣诞节
normal Christmas...
蛋奶鸡尾酒, 一颗他妈的圣诞树,
Eggnog, a fucking Christmas tree,
来点火鸡
a little turkey...
可是不成… 我得在这
But, no, I got to crawl around
该死铁管子里头到处爬
in this motherfucking tin can.
我们在附属空中通道里
We're in the Annex Skywalk.
我看得见天线盒了
I can see the array.
弄好了我就通知你
I'll give you a call for a protocol test as soon as it's hot.
就这样了
That's all for now.
士官 还要些装备
Sergeant, we need some more equipment.
我想派个你的人回去拿
I'd like to send one of your guys back for it.
是 先生  没问题
Right, sir. You got it.
这他妈怎么一回事?
What the hell's going on?
嘿! 把那个放回去
Hey! Put that back on!
嘿,蠢货,你看我像是个什么?
Hey, asshole, what do I look like to you?
一个好打的靶
A sitting duck.
去逮他
Take him!
该死!
Shit!
我真恨我猜对了
Damn it. I hate it when I'm right.
小心 趴下
Look out! Get down!
趴着别动
Stay down!
干!
Fuck!
快! 快!
Come on.
狗娘养的!
Fucking son of a bitch.
我看你是死定了
I'm going to kick your fucking ass.
老天爷!
Jeez.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事 我必须到天线阵列那…
Yeah. Yeah. But the antenna array...
并且把它接上
I got to get to it and set it up.
趴下!
Get down!
该死的!
Goddamn.
是个饵
Bait.
摆我们一道
Jerk us off,
罗伦佐最棒的手下都牺牲了
make Lorenzo sacrifice his best men.
让我们浪费时间
Make you waste your time...
而我们又分秒必争
time we don't have.
你可是比五十码还要近呢
I think you're closer than 50 yards.
那架飞机也是 实际上…
So's that airplane. Practically.
是,还有不少呢
Yeah. There's quite a few of them out there.
看起来就像平常塞车
It looks like a regular traffic jam.
这倒一点也不寻常
There's nothing regular about it.
看吧? 你开始感兴趣了
See? You're intrigued.
这是我的天赋, 麦克莱女士
That's my gift, Mrs. McClane.
我注意到的事…
I notice things...
是别人不会看到的
things other people wouldn't see.
所以我有办法使人们好奇
That's how I make people curious.
你是说恶心吧?
Don't you mean nauseous?
公众有权知道
Look. The people have a right to know
每个人的一切
everything about everybody.
而你却从中阻扰
You got in the way of that.
听着 小东西 你危害到我的孩子了
Listen, buster, you endangered my children,
你做的事的目的不会比普通民众高尚一丁点
and you didn't do it for anything as noble as the people.
你只有在有利可图向上爬的时候才会低下头
The only time you even see the people is when you look down
看看被你踩在脚下的大众
to see what it is you're stepping on.
我? 是,我死不了的
Me? Yeah, I'll live,
但罗伦佐的SWAT队全死了
but Lorenzo's S.W.A.T. team is dead,
而且天线阵列…也报销了
and the antenna array is gone.
你没看到爆炸吗?
Didn't you see it?
新的奇迹很难再发生
It's hard looking for a new miracle.
等一下
Just hold for a minute.
我马上再打来
I'll be right back.
等一下
Just hold for a second.
这里有事发生
Something's going on here.
对…再等一下
Yeah. Just hold on for a minute.
重复一遍 通道队 汇报情况
I say again, Annex Team, give us a sit rep.
通道队 听见了没有?
Annex Team, come in. Do you copy?
这上面有某种干扰装置
It's got some kind of scrambler on it.
你有办法对付它吗?
Can you do anything with it?
没办法.这个干扰模式
No. This scramble mode
必须得由这个密码控制台激活
must activate on this code panel.
就算扫瞄到他们的频率
Even if we scan their frequency,
我们也听不到
we can't listen in.
他们是专业的行家
These guys are pros.
你也是 破解那密码
So are you. Break the code.
我要听到那些混蛋正在说什么
I want to hear what these bastards are saying to each other.
这是10个数字控制面板
This is a 10...digit control panel.
六个数显读出装置
Six...digit read...out.
老天,密码组合要上百万个呢
Hell, there could be a million combinations.
下回你在杀这些人之前
Next time you kill one of these guys,
先叫他把密码给输入
get him to enter the code first.
是啊
Yeah.
长官!  我们刚监听到了一通电话
Sir, we just monitored a call from their chief engineer.
我们的人歼灭了SWAT队
Our people took out their S.W.A.T. team completely.
你猜对了 他们想动用那天线
You were right. They went for the antenna array.
计划进行顺利
We're right on schedule.
损失我们自己的人 可不在计划内
Losing our own team wasn't part of the plan.
注意 达拉斯指挥塔
Attention, Dulles Tower.
注意 控制塔台
Attention, Dulles Control Tower.
特鲁多先生 我知道你在听
Mr. Trudeau, I know you're listening.
不幸地 你没有服从指示
Unfortunately, you're not obeying.
来跟我单打独斗呀
Try me face to face, and we'll see.
已经警告过你不许修复系统
You were warned not to try to restore your systems.
你浪费了宝贵的人命和时间
You've wasted lives and precious time
在明显无用的目标上
on a futile and obvious target.
现在你要付出代价
Now you're going to pay the penalty.
我们死了五个警官 史都华上校
I've got five dead officers down here, Colonel Stuart.
这还罚得不够?
Isn't that penalty enough?
麦克莱 你别管这闲事!
McClane, you keep out of this.
否则让你痛不欲生
You've been nothing but a pain...
哦,麦克莱?  约翰 麦克莱?
Oh, McClane. John McClane.
营救中臣大厦人质的警察英雄
The policeman hero who saved the Nakatomi hostages.
我看过"人物"杂志 介绍你的文章
I read about you in People magazine.
在“今晚有约”上 你似乎有点失控
You seemed out of your league on Nightline, I thought.
嘿,上校 少你妈说废话
Hey, Colonel, blow me.
埃斯波兰萨给了你多少脏钱 让你叛变替他工作?
How much drug money is Esperanza paying you to turn traitor?
黎塞留主教说得好 叛国不过是时间的问题
Cardinal Richelieu said it best. Treason is merely a matter of dates.
这个国家必须学会…
This country's got to learn
不能一再阻扰像
that it can't keep cutting the legs off
像埃斯波兰萨将军这样的人
of men like General Esperanza,
这些有胆量起来对抗
men who have the guts to stand up
共党侵略的人
against Communist aggression.
那第一课就从杀警察开始?
And lesson one starts with killing policemen?
第二课是什么? 中子弹?
What's lesson two... the neutron bomb?
不是 我想可以找到中庸之道
No. I think we can find something in between.
等着瞧
Watch this.
告诉我一个 快没油的班机号码
Give me a flight number, one that's low on fuel.
伦敦来的温莎114
Windsor 114. Transatlantic from London.
油箱干得像干马提尼
Fuel tank's dry as a martini.
启动自动导航降落系统
Activate the I LS landing system,
重新校准海平面到…
but recalibrate sea level
负两百尺
minus 200 feet.
(高度)
天啊!
Oh,Jesus!
他们把地面高度降低了两百尺
They've reset ground level minus 200 feet.
温莎114班机
Windsor flight 114.
达拉斯机场导航呼叫
This is Dulles Approach.
听到请回答
Do you copy?
我是温莎114
Dulles Approach, this is Windsor 114.
你刚才死到哪里去了?
Where the devil have you been?
温莎114 达拉斯导航回报
Windsor 114. Dulles Approach.
我们一直都在这 老友
We've been right here all along, old buddy.
我们的系统一秒钟前才刚恢复正常
Our systems only came back on line just this very second.
温莎114 你可以使用自动导航仪降落了
Windsor 114, you are cleared for I LS approach,
使用第29跑道
runway two...niner.
进入进场程序时请联络塔台
Contact Dulles Tower frequency at the outer marker.
天啊 他会让那飞机坠毁
Jesus Christ,he's going to crash the fucking plane!
收到,进场, 该是时候了
Roger, Approach, and about time.
我这上头有230人 靠油气在飞
I've got 230 people up here flying on petrol fumes.
收到 114 明白
Roger, 114. Understand.
校准高度表
Calibrate Dulles altimeter...
老天爷
Oh,Jesus.
他们会撞上水泥地
They'll fly right into the concrete.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
他们为什么要听他的
Why are they listening to him?
他使用的是我们的专用频率 为什么不听?
It's our frequency! Why shouldn't they?
达拉斯机场 我是温莎114…
Dulles, this is Windsor 114.
巴恩!
Barnes!
这是达拉斯塔台 雷达上看到你了
This is Dulles Tower. We have radar contact...
把你的大衣给我
Give me your coat!
温莎114  待命
Windsor 114, stand by...
你想干什么?
What are you going to do?
尽我所能!
Whatever I can.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
也许你们注意到了 我们即将降落
as you've probably noticed, we've started our descent.
对延误感到抱歉
We're sorry for the inconvenience,
几分钟内 我们将要着陆了 谢谢
but we'll all be on the ground in a few minutes. Thank you.
请系上你的安全带
Please keep your seat belts on.
别担心
Oh, not to worry.
我们已经对你们下一趟飞机做了安排
We've made arrangements for your next flight,
你们不会错过转机的
so you won't miss it, O.K.?
请回到你的座位上…
In your seat, please.
快点 回到座位
Come on, in your seat.
我们就像英国的火车,亲爱的
We're just like British Rail, love.
可能会误点 但总会把你送到
We may be late, but we get you there.
别担心
Don't worry.
祝你好运 麦克莱
Good luck, McClane!
我是温莎114
Dulles, this is Windsor 114,
己进入进场程序
inside the outer marker.
收到 114 这是达拉斯塔台
Roger, 114. This is Dulles Tower.
你显示在雷达上 并在导航仪看到你
We have radar contact and show you on I LS.
你的方位正确 没有问题
You're in the glide path, and you're looking good.
那外头有个人
There's somebody out there!
是麦克莱
It's McClane.
老天爷
Christ.
放下襟翼
Approach flaps.
进场速度140节…
Approach speed 140.
130节
130.
高度 1000尺
Altitude 1,000 feet.
是800尺,老兄! 你们只有800尺!
800, guys! You're only at 800 feet!
带上紧急救援装备
Fire and Rescue, this is Cummings.
全都带着到29跑道
Roll everything out to runway two...niner!
规定空速加20
Ref speed plus 20.
600尺
600 feet.
看来很好 温莎
Looking good, Windsor.
注意
Now, watch it.
侧风30节 跑道上结了冰
30...knot crosswinds, and the runway is icy.
做得好 小子 我们会照顾你
Atta boy. We've got you.
我们看到你了
We've got you.
快升高
Pull it up!
老天
Jesus!
啊 我们要死了
Aah! We're going to die!
我们整到你了
We've got you.
不…
No...
天啊
God.
王八蛋
Motherfucker.
天啊
Oh,Jesus.
今晚的课程到此结束
That concludes our object lesson for this evening.
如果我们要的747按时备妥
If the 747 we requested is ready on time
并且埃斯波兰萨将军的飞机 不受干扰抵达
and General Esperanza's plane arrives unmolested,
下一堂可以不用上
further lessons can be avoided.
完毕
Out.
我们没发现生还者
We got no sign of survivors down here.
真是该死的恶梦
It's a goddamn nightmare.
尼尔逊 过来
Hey, Nelson! Come here.
巴恩!
Barnes!
我们得警告其他飞机
We've got to warn those planes
这里有个疯子
there's a lunatic down here.
让我跟天上的飞机通话
Get up to the cabin. Get me on the air.
怎么通?
How?
你去想法子
You figure it out!
这是旅客名单
Here's the manifest.
麦克莱, 我知道你的感受
McClane, I know how you must feel.
我真想帮那些人
I wanted to help those people.
我他妈的真没用
I was pretty goddamn useless.
我们已经联邦政府求救
We called the government for help.
他们会派个特殊兵种
They're going to send in a special Army unit,
叫反恐特攻队
a counterterrorist team.
尊夫人的飞机…
Your wife's plane?
他们仍在呼叫
Well, they're still broadcasting
但是我们无法回答
even though we can't answer them.
九十分钟后他们就没油了
They're going to run out of fuel in 90 minutes.
听着 迪克
Listen, Dick.
那是你名字没错吧?
That is your name?
迪克(混帐)
Dick.
如果你要继续靠得这么近
If you're going to continue to get this close,
你是否可以考虑...
do you think you might consider
换换刮胡水
switching after...shaves?
还要换别的吗?
Anything else?
强力漱口水也不错
Stronger mouthwash might be nice.
我是萨姆·坷曼
And here's Sam Coleman
正在事故现场给您报道
reporting live from the site of the accident.
呃,上校
Well, Colonel,
我们猜到他们所有行动
they've done everything we've anticipated...
…到目前为止
so far.
官方仍然没有发布任何消息
But still there has been no official word.
虽然只有一条跑道
Meanwhile, despite the fact only one runway
因发生惨剧而关闭
has been closed due to the tragedy,
但从我站的这里仍可以看到许多飞机
several dozen airliners are visible from where I stand,
在不断围着机场盘旋着
endlessly circling the field.
另有消息称在飞机坠毁前,指挥塔内
Other reports say that there was trouble in the tower
发生了大麻烦
before the crash
这也许也是造成坠机事故的原因之一
and that that may have even contributed to it.
有一件事能确定
One thing is certain.
随着天气逐渐转坏
With weather conditions worsening,
地上和天上的麻烦
the problem here and in the sky above us
将越来越大
will continue to grow.
莎曼萨柯曼 在达拉斯国际机场报导
I'm Samantha Coleman at Dulles International Airport.
维克多 维克多
Victor. Victor.
嘿 怎么了
Yeah, what's up?
你把无线麦克风放在行李里…
Did you pack the radio mikes from the shoot,
还是带在身上?
or did you put them in your carry...on?
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
我才不会让那些混球没收
I wouldn't let those assholes check them in.
我爱你
I love you.
给我一具接收器
Give me one of the receivers.
你能把它调到机师舱频率吗?
Can you tune in to the cockpit frequency?
可以 为什么?
Yeah. Why?
我要听听现在怎么样了
I want to hear what's going on.
应该就是这个频率了
Should be right here on our band.
什么也听不见
Nothing.
你刚才说能行的
You just told me it would work.
它到底有没有用呀?
Is it working or not working?
它有用 不过…
It is working, but it's...
我只听到一些机场信号
All I'm getting is some kind of airport beacon.
怪了
It's weird.
好像是指挥塔不存在了
It's like the tower isn't there.
继续听吧
Stay on it.
听到动静后马上告诉我
Let me know when there is something there.
好的!
O.K.
葛蓝少校 我们能行动了
Major Grant. We're Blue Light.
罗林 司法部
Rollins, Department of Justice.
特鲁多 飞务总管
Trudeau, Chief of Air Operations.
罗伦佐 航警局局长
Lorenzo, Terminal Police.
你要的一切 全力支援
You want something, you got it.
就这些人?
This is it?
一个排的兵力?
One fucking platoon?
一个危机一个排 你是谁?
One Crisis...1 Platoon. Who are you?
约翰·麦克莱!
John McClane.
麦克莱, 你刚才表现很有种.
McClane, you showed some balls out there, man.
是呀!
Yeah.
但现在表现些理智
Now show some good sense.
让专家来处理
Let the pros handle this.
是的,不过今晚看来专家是在敌对那一边
Yeah, well, it looks like the pros are on the wrong team tonight.
史都华上校不正是你们的人吗?
Isn't Colonel Stuart one of your men?
不,不再是了,他不是
No, not anymore, he's not.
我们是来这儿搞掂他的
Now we're here to take Colonel Stuart down.
我们一定会搞掂他的
And we will take him down.
我跟他是同事
You see, I served with him.
他什么都是我教的
I taught him everything he knows.
呃,也许他还学会了一些别的
Well, maybe he's learned a few more things since then.
动作快!
Let's hustle!
指挥所设在
The command post will be set up
机场警察局里
in the airport police station.
我要在十五分钟内 接通塔台通讯
I want to be tied in to the tower in 15 minutes.
好吧,我们动手吧!
All right, let's do it!
嘿 特鲁多
Hey, Trudeau.
事情好转了还是更糟了?
Did things just get better or worse?
灯光 大型、可携带的灯光
Lights... big, portable lights.
我们把这些放在跑道上 然后…
We set up the field, and then we...
等那些疯子把灯全部打掉?
We wait for those lunatics to shoot them out.
我们到哪去弄大型便携灯光?
And where do we get those big, portable lights...
从蝙蝠侠那里借?
Borrow them from Batman?
无线电话的主意呢?
What about the airphone idea?
上头有十八架飞机
There's 18 planes up there.
只有五架有电话
Only five of them have those phones.
我们跟其中三架通话成功
We got through to three of them.
其他的还在试
We're still trying on the others.
那就等着要发生十三件意外
That leaves 13 accidents waiting to happen.
逆风情况如何?
Are they still bucking head winds?
我刚看过气象 外指点标方位的飞机都是顶风
I just checked the weather. Head winds are slamming everybody over the outer marker.
有足够油料的飞机都已经转往亚特兰大
The planes with enough fuel have already been shunted to Atlanta
曼菲斯和纳许维尔
Memphis, and Nashville.
外指点标示
Outer marker.
该死的
Damn!
那个外指点标示
The outer marker!
这是一种信号,对吗? 会发出哔哔哔的信号
It's a beacon, right? It sends out this "beep beep beep"
这样他们就会知道 他们飞越了它 对吧?
so they know they're over it, right?
- 又怎样? - 谁说无线电只能发出哔哔声?
- So? - So who says that radio signal has to just beep?
好的. 把塔台频率换到发信标频率
Right. We switch the frequency from the tower over to the one in the beacon.
增加输出功率
We pump up the wattage.
我们就能跟我们飞机通话
And we can talk to our planes,
那些杂种绝对不会发现
and those bastards who did this will never know!
追踪信号来源
Traced the signal.
在行李区发现的
Found it in the luggage area.
他们整晚在窃听你们塔台的电话
They've been tapped in to your tower chatter all night.
小贼偷行李 嗯?  卡麦?
Punks stealing luggage, huh, Carmine?
你进行的如何了? 德福
How you doing, Telford?
毫无进展
No good.
我通知林了
I called Lang.
他们正在装配一个便携解码器,两小时内会送来
They're rigging a portable decoder. It'll be here in two hours.
我老婆可坚持不了两个小时
My wife doesn't have two hours.
我才刚转到葛蓝队上一天
I was only transferred to Grant's team yesterday.
因为原本的人得了阑尾炎
The regular guy got appendicitis.
可是葛蓝少校是最棒的
Word is, nobody's better at this than Major Grant.
立正
Attention!
也许除了史都华上校
Except maybe Colonel Stuart.
我要得知他们要求的那架飞机的情况
I want to hear about the plane those bastards asked for.
然后再告诉你们我的命令
Then I'll fill you in on my orders.
现在到机师简报室去
Pilots' briefing room. Now.
继续努力
Keep working.
艾伯逊! 跟我来
Albertson. With me.
平民不能参加
No civilians.
搞什么?
What the fuck?
怎么了?
What is it?
外指点标发射器不哔哔叫了
The outer marker beeper. It isn't beeping.
它在说话
It's talking.
达拉斯机场 所有准备进场飞机注意
Attention all aircraft in Dulles landing pattern.
我是总工程师莱斯利 巴恩
This is Chief Engineer Leslie Barnes.
我经授权向各位简报全部情况
I have been authorized to brief you in full.
目前 这是我们唯一可用的频道
At this time, this is the only channel available to us.
情况是这样的
Here is the situation.
大概在两个小时以前…
Approximately two hours ago...
一直等到你听到大量这样的声音
Wait until you get a load of this.
不要接受任何声称来自指挥塔的指令
Do not accept any instructions claiming to be from our tower
除非你听到你自己飞机飞行记录仪的访问密码
unless you hear your own flight recoder access code.
- 恐怖份子破坏了我们所有系统 - 妈的
- The terrorists have got all our systems and now... - Holy shit!
把这段录下来
Get this on tape!
控制了一切 除了这个频道
have control of everything except this channel.
给我一会就行 求你了
Give us a second here, please.
这个频道是安全的 你们自己的通信却不是
This channel is secure. Your own transmissions are not.
不要试图,重复一遍,不要试图
Do not, repeat, do not attempt
用你们的频率
to reply on your own frequencies
回答这个播音
to this broadcast.
他们模仿我们指挥塔已经造成了一架飞机的坠毁
These people have already caused one crash by impersonating our tower.
老天爷!
Jesus.
再重复一遍 恐怖份子已经切断了
Repeat. The terrorists have cut off
降落的两套系统
the two systems that can allow you to land...
包括目视降落的机场指示灯光
field lights for a visual landing
及自动导航降落仪
and the ILS for an instrument.
一支美军特遣队已经到达这里
A special U.S. Army unit is already here
正准备消灭这帮恐怖份子
and preparing to take out the terrorists.
老天爷
My God.
嗨 马文
Yo, Marvin.
要一件好大衣吗?
Hey, you interested in a nice coat?
我穿从来都不好看
No. It never looked good on me anyway.
听着,你必须让我去到机师简报室
Listen, you've got to get me up to the pilots' briefing room.
我得听听他们都说些什么
I've got to hear what they're saying.
那一张图才能让我找到那儿…
Which one of these maps gets me in there?
别碰它! 别碰它!
Don't touch it! Don't touch it!
- 把图找出来,马文 - 我会找到
- Find the map, Marvin. - I'll find it.
你会把我的档案系统全弄乱的
You'll mess up my whole damn filing system here.
我想想 机师简报室...
Let's see. Pilots' Briefing Room.
我认为是在主航站大楼里
I think that's in the main terminal,
那么这个P是不是指的是机师简报室?
so would that be under " P" for Pilots' Briefing Room?
或者也许是...
Or maybe it would be...
在M下面 杂物间
under " M" for Miscellaneous.
妈的
Oh, shit!
要求准许岗哨减至
Request permission to reduce sentry duty
三十分换一班
to 30...minute rotation.
我手下又冷又不耐烦 完毕
My men are getting cold and antsy. Over.
我是史都华上校
This is Colonel Stuart.
把没有站岗的人集合起来听简报 完毕
Have the men not on watch assemble for a briefing. Over
收到 上校
Roger, Colonel.
怎么回事?
What's the matter?
各位
Gentlemen...
今晚过后 旧的格局将结束
Tonight, the pattern ends.
多米诺骨牌不再倒下…
The dominoes will fall no more,
堡垒仍维持坚固
and the ramparts will remain upright.
长官 埃斯波兰萨将军的飞机
Sir, General Esperanza's plane
刚进入荧幕
just came on the scope.
注意 达拉斯塔台
Attention, Dulles Tower.
我们要打开一个跑道的照明
We will be lighting up a runway.
不要 重复 不要企图让任何飞机降落
Do not, repeat, do not attempt to land any planes.
记住 我们在监视你们
Remember, we're monitoring you.
我们怎么办?
What do we do?
服从
Obey.
达拉斯塔台呼叫 狐步舞迈克一号
Dulles Tower to Fox Trot Michael One.
我是狐步舞迈克一号, 达拉斯
This is Fox Trot Michael One, Dulles.
听到了 完毕
We read you. Over.
狐步舞迈克一号 你要在15跑道上降落
Fox Trot Michael One, you are to come in on runway 15,
重复 15
repeat, 15.
我在行李输送带旁
I found it on the floor, by the coat,
地上发现的
next to the luggage belt.
你到底这么兴奋干嘛?
What the hell you so excited about that for?
这玩意仍在接受信号
The code's still punched into this one.
你喜欢?
You like it, huh?
二十块钱卖给你如何?
How about giving me 20 bucks for it?
那我让你活下去如何?
How about I let you live?
你真会讨价还价
Man knows how to bargain.
这和我们原先的指令相反
This is contrary to our instructions.
我们应该在10号跑道降落
We are to land at runway 10,
并且和你们司法部的代表…
where we are to be met by representatives of your justice de...
机长,请告诉指挥塔
Captain, please tell the tower
你会照指令行事
you will proceed as ordered.
收到 达拉斯
Roger, Dulles.
继续飞向第15号跑道
Proceeding to runway 15.
狐步舞迈克一号 请回答
Foxtrot Michael One. Come in, please.
你现在要怎样?
What are you going to do now?
把我杀了?
Are you going to shoot me?
谁来飞这架飞机?
So who will fly the plane?
别操心
Don't worry about it.
不是你的问题了
It's not your problem.
迈克1号 听到没?
Michael One. Do you copy?
狐步舞迈克一号 请回答
Foxtrot Michael One. Come in, please.
鹰巢
Eagle Nest.
这是猎鹰 求助
This is Falcon. Mayday.
鹰巢 这是猎鹰 求助
Eagle Nest. This is Falcon. Mayday!
请讲 猎鹰
Go ahead, Falcon.
我失去了舱压 能见度近乎零
I've lost cabin pressure. Near zero visibility.
我必须躲避天气 得马上降落
I must drop out of this weather and land now,
在最近的跑道上
on the first accessible runway.
重复
Repeat.
我失去了舱压 能见度近乎零
I've lost cabin pressure. Near zero visibility.
我必须脱离这暴风
I must drop out of the storm.
我可以降落 但必须马上降落
I can land, but I must land now,
在最近的跑道上
on the first outgoing runway.
重复 我不能绕到
Repeat. I cannot circle around
15跑道去了
to runway 15.
我们做个交易 马文
I'll make you a deal, Marvin.
你告诉我去跑道的捷径
You show me a shortcut out to those runways,
我就给你弄件大衣的衬里
and I'll get you a liner for that coat.
重复 我不能绕到15跑道去了
Repeat. I cannot circle around to runway 15.
他妈的!
Shit.
待命 猎鹰
Stand by, Falcon.
这里 长官
Here, sir.
他从海洋的方向飞过来
He's coming in from the ocean.
一颗子弹弄坏了我的仪表
A bullet has damaged my instruments.
我不能确定我的方位
I'm not sure of my bearings,
我必须马上目视降落
and I must make a visual landing immediately.
听到了没 鹰巢?
Do you copy, Eagle Nest?
好的 猎鹰
Roger, Falcon.
使用右25跑道
That would be 25 right.
重复 右25跑道
Repeat. 25 right.
打定主意呀
Make up your fucking mind!
又碰上 爱耍人的恐怖份子了 约翰
Oh, we are just up to our ass in terrorists again,John.
确认 右25 完毕
Affirmative. 25 right. Over.
右25
25 right.
我一定得戒烟了
I've got to quit smoking cigarettes.
谢谢你告诉我 鹰巢
Thank you for telling me, Eagle Nest.
但如果你能打开跑道照明
But if you could show it to me as well,
我会很感激
I would be grateful.
我看到灯光了
I see the lights.
就在我正前方
They are directly in front of me.
谢谢你 老友
Gracias, compadre.
降低空速 接近跑道
Reducing air speed. Approaching runway.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
收到 猎鹰
Roger, Falcon.
我们听到了 五分钟后见
We copy. We'll have you in five minutes.
没错 混蛋…
That's right, asshole.
五分钟后就捉到你们了
We'll have you in five minutes.
我看见灯了
I see your lights.
预备九十秒降落
ETA 90 seconds.
到老爸这儿来 废物
Come to papa, scumbag.
不
No!
自由
Freedom.
还没有喔!
Not yet.
在飞机到停机坪前
You're supposed to stay in your seat
你应该继续坐着
until the plane reaches the terminal.
看样子不常坐飞机
No frequent...flier mileage for you.
你是谁?
Who are you?
警察
A cop.
警察?
A cop?
对 我是好人
Yeah, one of the good guys.
而你是坏人
You're one of the bad guys,
既然你在我手上,我得拿你换我老婆
and now that I got your sorry ass, I'm going to trade it for my wife.
坐下
Sit down!
进去!
Go in!
他去哪了?
Where did he go?
在那里头
In there.
我不信有这种事
I don't believe this.
两个月计划…
Two months of planning,
没料到有笨警察
and you can't anticipate one pendejo of a cop.
走吧 将军!
Come on, General.
史都华上校到底在哪里?
Where the hell is Colonel Stuart?
将军!
General!
啊!我没事
Ah! I'm all right.
他说他是个警察
He said he was a policeman.
我还以为你肃清了这个地方
I thought you had this place secured.
他到机师舱里去了
He went in the cockpit.
马上要他的命
He's going to hell!
麦克莱
McClane!
我猜这是你 麦克莱
I assume it's you, McClane.
你是个不错的小战士
You're quite a little soldier.
你可以把这个当成一个军方葬礼
You can consider this a military funeral!
我们有几个手榴弹
How many grenades we got?
每人三个
Three each!
都丢进去
Use them!
老天!
Oh, my...
走!
Go!
啊
Aah!
他妈的!
Oh, shit!
你这幸运的混蛋
You lucky fuck.
救火车来了 长官
Fire trucks, sir.
退回到教堂去 现在
Fall back to the church. Now!
他妈的门呢?
Where's the fucking door?
旅客们很紧张
They're getting a little nervous back there.
事实上 我也是
In fact, so am I.
我们就在华盛顿上空
We're right over Washington.
看你能否打开电视
See if you can get any TV.
让他们平静下来
That will settle them down.
是我的工作 我…
Works for me. I'll...
(油料控制)
写铁钟奖最差节目受奖答词?
Writing your acceptance speech for the Video Sleaze Awards?
普力兹奖还差不多
Try Pulitzer.
先生们女士们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们等待降落时
while waiting to land, our cabin attendants
将播送华盛顿当地节目
are turning on local Washington broadcasting.
声音在第三频道
The sound is on channel three.
好
O.K.
好 好
O.K., O.K.
拜托 先生 我们随时都会降落
Please, sir, we may land at any moment.
请你坐到位子上…
If you'll take your seat...
我想呕吐 抱歉 我想吐…
I'm going to be sick. Excuse me. I'm going to be sick.
安全带的灯亮了
Sir, the seat belt light is on.
蠢蛋!
Moron.
WZDC新闻台
WZDC.
我是理查德 索伯
Yes, this is Richard Thornberg.
给我接新闻室的鲁本
Put me through to Ruben in the newsroom.
他就要直播了…
Uh, he's about to go live...
我知道马上要播出
I know he's about to go on.
但我需要他
That's why I need him.
你得等一下...
You'll have to hold on...
给我转过去,西莉娅
Put me through, Celia,
不然就准备写自己的简历去
or start typing your resume.
埃斯波兰萨降落了
Esperanza's down...
可是他受了伤
But he's hurt.
他肩膀上挨了一枪
He took a round in his shoulder.
我还杀了另外一个
Plus I got one more of their guys.
他们已经一共损失六个人了
That's six they lost altogether.
要是能知道 他们总共有多少人
Maybe if we knew how many they had to start with,
我们才高兴得起来
we could get excited,
如果他们有五十人
but if they got 50 guys,
就别太急着开香槟庆祝了
it's a little early to break out the champagne!
麦克莱 我欣赏你的努力
Now, we appreciate your effort, McClane,
但我不需要自行其事的人
but we don't need a loose cannon on this deck!
要是他们决定再弄毁另一架飞机
What if they decide to crash another plane
来报复你的小把戏呢?
in retaliation for your little stunt?
他们办不到了 对吧 巴恩?
They can't do that anymore, right, Barnes?
要是我已经捉到埃斯波兰萨
Besides, if I grabbed Esperanza,
现在就全部搞掂了
this would all be over by now.
呃,如果他们比你想的 更难对付呢?
Well, maybe they're just a little bit more creative than you think!
至少我有计划 该死
Well, at least I'm thinking, goddamn it!
给我听好
Listen, you wise...ass,
在他们离地前 与他们战斗是我的责任
we're here to jerk off that cocksucker until he tries to take off.
就这样!
Period!
你现身的地点及时间都不对
Now, you're the wrong guy in the wrong place at the wrong time!
这事老发生在我身上
The story of my life.
少校!
Major,
五角大厦战况室来电
Pentagon situation room, sir!
五角大厦…
Pentagon.
我在这里接
I'll take it in here.
谢谢 德福
Thank you, Telford.
你们这些人跟我来
You men come with me.
麦克莱
McClane.
怎样 巴恩?
Yeah, Barnes.
你说那些恐怖份子立刻就现身了
You said those guys showed up out there right away?
恩？
Yeah.
那他们一定在跑道上 或是在附近
That means they're on the field or close,
我想我知道是哪里
and I think I know where.
过来 我给你看一样东西
Come here. Let me show you something.
这是十二年前
These are the old plans when the longer runways went in.
兴建长跑道的计划
That's 12 years ago.
看起来他们对 航站大厦做了些修改
Looks like they've done some modifications on site...
雷达、电话和导航仪…
moved Tra Con phones, I LS,
所有地下的玩意 都被移动
all the underground stuff
以便对排水道施工
so they could handle drainage.
如果我想的没错
If I'm right,
线路会顺着机场
all of it would run right along the airport property
通到这附近
and go right past this neighborhood.
我们两小时前就该降落了!
We should have been on the ground two hours ago!
我明白 请你放轻松…
I understand, but if you just relax...
没希望了
It's hopeless.
弄得这一团糟 得有人挨揍才对
Somebody ought to get their ass kicked for this mess, that's for sure.
恩 很不幸
Well, unfortunately,
天气是这样的 我们谁也不能怪
there really isn't anyone we can blame for the weather.
是吗?  那个报气象的老俊男呢?
Oh, yeah? What about that porker Willard Scott?
我该坐巴士的
I should have taken the bus.
至少他们能停下来 吃东西及加油
At least they can pull over for food and gas.
抱歉!
Excuse me.
怎样?
Yes?
我只是不明白…
I was just wondering.
飞行时间原定是
This flight originally
五个半小时 对不对?
was supposed to be 5  half a hours, right?
我们有足够的油料吗?
Do we have enough fuel?
让我们不停绕圈?
to keep circling like this?
当然有
Oh, of course.
他们预先想到类似这样的问题了
They anticipate little problems like this.
巴恩, 我们看了他妈12个房子
Barnes, we looked at 12 fucking houses,
什么也没有
and we're nowhere.
这是最后一个可能了
This is our last possibility.
在这里有一所旧教堂
Over here there's an old church.
我们走
Let's go.
等等
Wait.
教堂在那里
There's the church over there.
也许是个岗哨
Could be a sentry.
也可能是出来散步的
And he could just be out for a walk.
那为什么来回走来走去?
Then why is he going over his own footsteps?
快来
Come on.
好吧
All right.
待在这儿 准备叫陆战队的人来
Just stay here and get ready to call the marines.
我以为他们是陆军来的
I thought they were the army.
管他妈的 准备好就行了
Who gives a fuck? Just be ready.
糟了!
Oh, shit.
现在别响!
Not now.
啊
Aah!
罗伦佐 我是巴恩
Lorenzo, it's Barnes.
巴恩 你们到底去了哪里?
Barnes, where the hell did you go?
麦克莱呢?
Where's McClane?
他和我在一起 我们在机场西侧的教堂
He's with me. We're at the Hidey Lake Community Church on the west side of the airport.
你们在哪儿?  该死
You're where? Goddamn it!
你这神经白痴 怎么...
You crazy idiot, why didn't...
他们的行动基地在这里
This must be their base of operations.
闭上嘴 赶紧过来
Shut up and get your ass over here!
快点
Move it!
红色警戒 更新情报
Code red! Sit rep.
我们确定了史都华的位置
We got positive I.D. on Stuart's location.
动身吧
Let's move.
我们撤离的飞机会在
Our escape plane will be ready
三十分钟内准备好 将军
within 30 minutes, General.
如果没有意外的话
If there are no more surprises.
各位 我们这里有状况
Gentlemen, we have a situation here.
啊
Aah!
哦
Oh!
在这边
Over here.
老天 麦克莱 你还好吧? 要医护兵吗?
Jeez, McClane, you all right? You want a medic?
麦克莱 你以为你在干什么?
What the hell you think you're doing out there,
扮牛仔吗?
playing John Wayne?
想不想在看守所待一夜?
How would you like to spend the night in a cell?
罗伦佐 闭上鸟嘴 去做些有用的事
Lorenzo, shut the fuck up and do something useful.
去把路封了
Go seal off the street.
嘿,你不能这样对我说话
Hey, you can't talk to me like that.
哦,不行吗? 卡麦
Oh, no, Carmine?
士官 马上让这个白痴官僚在麦克莱先生面前消失
Sergeant, get this bureaucrat out of Mr. McClane's face now.
愿意效劳 长官
With pleasure, sir.
少校
Major...
大家都就位了
the men are in position, sir.
包围后面再进去
Close up the back. Then we go in.
听我口令开火
Fire only on my order.
遵命 长官
Roger that, sir.
我猜我想错你了
Guess I was wrong about you.
终究你不是那么混帐
You're not such an asshole after all.
不 你是对的
No, you were right.
我跟你一样混帐
I'm just your kind of asshole.
嘉伯 情况汇告!
Garber, sit rep!
陆军特遣队从三面包围我们
Army Special Forces on three sides, closing in fast around the back!
又出问题了? 上校!
Another problem, Colonel?
没问题 将军
No problem, General.
各位 你们知道怎么处理
Gentlemen, you know what to do.
趴下!
Down!
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
将军 是时候了
General... it's time.
快 我们走
Come on, let's move it!
他们撤退了!
They're pulling out out the back!
快!
Move it!
艾伯逊 叫你手下绕到后头
Albertson, take your men around the back.
啊
Aah!
这些设备能让飞机降落
This equipment, it could land our planes.
别碰 他们可能装了诡雷…
There were trip wires outside. They could have booby...trapped...
他们的确装了
They did.
这里也有一个
Got one here, too.
像是塑胶炸弹 而且已经武装了
Looks like C...4. The motherfucker is armed.
所有的人 离开这里
Clear the area! Everybody, now!
他们在设备上装了诡雷
They booby...trapped all the equipment.
把教堂封闭起来
Seal off the building!
他妈的!
Shit!
派警卫 不准任何人接近
Post sentries. No civilians allowed.
嘿! 狗日的麦克莱呢?
Hey, where the fuck is McClane?
米勒 干掉他
Miller, take him!
我掩护你
I'll cover you!
这下可永绝后患了
So much for the element of chance.
出发吧
Let's move out.
我明明有瞄到那杂种
I had the bastard in my sights.
我知道我有
I know I did.
老天爷
Oh,Jesus Christ.
注意,指挥塔注意 达拉斯指挥塔注意
Attention, Tower. Attention, Dulles Tower.
我是史都华上校 我们的飞机准备好没?
This is Colonel Stuart. Is our plane prepared?
好了 在第11号机棚里
It is. It's in hangar 11.
距此最远的建筑物
It's the most remote building we've got.
我们这就去
We're on our way.
派一组地勤人员 检查飞机的适飞状况
Have a ground crew there to confirm the condition of the plane.
你们相信那家伙 真有这个种吗?
Do you believe the balls on this son of a bitch?
上校 你自己就有 足够的能力去检查
Colonel, you're quite capable of confirming it yourself.
别想让我们奉送人质
Now, please, don't ask us to gift...wrap potential hostages for you.
葛蓝少校 是吗?
Major Grant, isn't it?
要是你记得我…上校
If you remember me, Colonel,
那你该记得我也懂这一套
then you remember I know the drill as well as you do.
自己去检查该死的飞机吧!
Check out your own fucking plane.
五分钟后行动
We move out in five minutes.
每个人都穿上防弹衣
Flak jackets for everybody.
突击组着全身护甲
Body armor for the assault team.
狙击手要带红外线瞄准镜
Night scopes for the snipers.
我们到机棚去对付他们
We will take them in the hangar,
我要亲自把引爆器
and I will pull that detonator
从史都华的尸体上取过来
out of Stuart's dead fucking hand myself.
罗伦佐 带你手下回到机场
Take all your men back to the airport.
把所有的出口都封闭
Seal off every exit
以防有人溜过防线
in case they try to slip past us
趁机脱逃出去
to break out onto the ground.
没问题
You got it.
好了 我们走
All right, here we go.
迪克 这真是疯了
Dick, this is nuts.
每家电视台都派了人在机场
Every station in town has people out at the airport,
可是你说的这事可没人听过
and none of them has heard even a whisper of this shit you're running now!
他们可不像我
Well, none of them is me.
要证据吗? 听听这个
You want proof, try this.
“重复 恐怖份子谋杀了许多平民”
Repeat. Terrorists have murdered civilians
“切断了让你们降落的系统设备”
and cut off the two systems that can allow you to land.
“陆军特遣队 己到这
A special U.S. Army unit is already here
包围恐怖份子”
and preparing to take out the terrorists.
老天
Jesus Christ.
我要你马上直播出去
I want you to go live now.
用我的相片 从档案里面取
Get me in from the files... a publicity shot.
找一张地图 去气象部偷一张
Connie's got one. The maps...get one from weather.
正在办了 我们五分钟后做插播
We're on it. We're cutting in five minutes!
告诉友台如果他们也要联播
Tell the affiliates if they want in,
他们得在三分钟内知会
they got three minutes to shout.
咱们来干吧!
Let's do this.
全国电视网 我来了
Network, here I come.
德福 我们去格瑞纳达时
Hey, Telford, what was your chicken shit outfit doing
你干嘛穿得跟雪人一样?
while we were taking Grenada?
格瑞纳达 交火五分钟
Grenada... five minutes of fire fight,
冲浪五星期
five weeks of surfing.
我真希望我也有去
I wish I was with you guys for that.
对 我也是 孩子
Yeah. Me, too, kid.
真的 长官?
Really, sir?
当然
Sure.
那我们就用不着这么做了
Then we wouldn't have to do this.
鹰巢 我是幼鹰
Eagle Nest, this is Hatchling.
按时到了指定位置
On schedule... and in position.
知道了 幼鹰 我们这里很平静
Roger, Hatchling. We are secure here.
你可以进行了
You have a green light.
我重复 可以进行
I repeat, a green light.
老天 警官 你从那里来的?
Jesus, Officer, where did you come from,
珍珠港?
Pearl Harbor?
好了 清场 拜托
All right, let's clear it out, please.
准备
Stand by.
五…四…三…
5, 4, 3...
WZDC新闻 特别新闻快报
This is a special bulletin from WZDC News.
今晚早些时候达拉斯机场发生坠机事件
There was a plane crash earlier this evening at Dulles,
其他飞机仍在当地继续盘旋
where other aircraft continue to circle,
机场或航空局官方 均未发表声明
with no explanation from airport or FAA officials.
现在WZDC独家报导…
And now, with an exclusive WZDC report,
迪克索伯自华盛顿上空报导
here's Dick Thornberg reporting from the skies over Washington.
我是在华府上空盘旋着的
I'm one of the thousand people
千名旅客之一
who has been circling our nation's capital
我们假定在下方发生的情况
under the assumption that whatever problem
只是一般常发生的小错误
was going on far below was a normal one,
然而事实与想像相距甚远
but the truth is far from normal.
事实很可怕
The truth is terrifying.
让开 女士 让开
Look out! Lady, look out!
小心!
Look out! Look out!
当心,让开
Look out! Look out! Get out of the way!
走开啊!
Get out of the way!
女士 走开
Get out of the way, lady!
快  嘿 嘿 小心
Go, go, go! Hey, hey, look out!
以下的录音是
This is a recording of a conversation
塔台 和盘旋飞机之间的对话
between Dulles Tower and a captive aircraft overhead.
让开
Get out of the way!
罗伦佐
Lorenzo!
麦克莱,你他妈的疯了吗?
McClane, are you out of your fucking mind?
陆军特遣队在哪里
The Blue Light team... where are they?
史都华在教堂 装了摇控爆炸装置
Stuart's got explosives in the church rigged with a remote.
葛蓝呢?
Where's Grant?
葛蓝和他手下 正要去把他杀了
They're going to kill that son of a bitch and get it from them!
他们不会这么做
They're not going to do that!
不 他们是要跟他一起上飞机
They're going to get on the same plane with him and take off with him!
他妈的滚出去
Get the fuck out of here!
军方解雇史都华的时候
When the army canned Stuart,
他已经把自己人马都安插进去了
he loaded that unit with his own men!
你疯了吗? 那场枪战…
Are you nuts? That fire fight...
那只是换取时间的烟火秀
Sideshow to buy them some time.
麦克莱 你真是疯子 你知道吗?
McClane, you are completely around the fucking bend.
同时你被捕了 你他妈的!
You're under arrest, you motherfucker.
这个就是他们今晚 所使用的子弹
Here! These are the bullets they used out there tonight!
空心弹
Blanks!
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
我是罗伦佐局长
This is Chief Lorenzo.
五分钟后我要所有警官
I want every officer recalled
集合全员全副武装
and assembled in body armor and full weaponry
备摩托雪橇
in the motor pool in five minutes.
准备砍人啰!
It's time to kick ass.
就像在硫磺岛
Just like IwoJima!
我们获悉 恐怖份子
This reporter has learned that the terrorists
已经实质控制了机场
have virtual control of the entire airport,
此一被当局所隐瞒的真相
a fact that the authorities have repressed.
除非满足恐怖分子提出的要求
The terrorists promise more bloodshed
否则他们声称会有更多 流血事件发生
unless their demands are met,
现在陆军特遣队
and now that the Special Army commandos
己抵达机场
have arrived at the airport,
一场生死之战将是不可避免的
the likelihood of a full...scale, deadly battle is dangerously close.
那个愚蠢傲慢的混帐…
That stupid, arrogant son of a bitch.
已经传遍了机场
It's all over the airport.
300人已经死亡
300 people have died...
我们什么时候降落
When are we going to land?
不幸的是 他们不是最后的牺牲者
...and unfortunately they may not be the last.
令人惊恐的事实是 没有人是安全的
The horrifying fact is that no one is safe,
无论是上方的飞机
either in the planes above Dulles
或是下方的航站
or in the terminal below.
那种不论你我 随时会死去的恐惧
The threat of a new and higher body count at the airport
使所有的人备感威胁
hangs over the heads of everyone,
而充满宁静和爱的假期
and the holiday season of peace and love
现在变成了可怕的恶梦
has become a nightmare.
好 各单位注意!
All right, listen up!
我要全员于11号机棚集合
All units, I want you to converge on hangar 11,
全面包围!
all sides!
这辆车 麦克莱 上车
This car, McClane! Get in!
等市警局的后备人员到达时…
When the City Blue show up with their backup,
他们只负责收尸了
they'll pick up the pieces!
出发!
Now, move out!
麦克莱 见过我弟弟维多
McClane, say hi to my brother Vito.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
嗨
Hi.
该死的 搞什么!
Goddamn it to hell!
把这破车开走!
Move that piece of shit!
你开走好吗?
Will you move that goddamn piece of shit out of here?
维多 给我滚下来
Vito, get the fuck out of the car
过来帮我把这车弄走
and get your ass in gear and help me.
你能...
Will you get...
马上把车移走!
Move that car right now!
就在那 拍那里!
Right there. Right there. Get that.
嘿 柯曼
Hey, Coleman!
莎曼萨柯曼!
Sam! Sam Coleman!
柯曼!
Hey, Coleman!
Coleman!
不过至少人质并不晓得真相
But at least the truth is not among the hostages
因为在下理查索伯 凑巧在此地
because I, Richard Thornberg, just happened to be here
将我的生命和才干
to put his life and talent
奉献给人性和国家
on the line for humanity and country,
这也许是我最后一次播报
and if this should be my final broadcast...
阿门!  迪克(混帐)!
Amen to that... Dick.
迪克! 我们在直播呢? 迪克
Dick? We're live, Dick.
你在哪里?
Where are you now?
迪克
Dick?
有卡车接近 先生
Truck lights approaching, sir.
他们到了 完全按计划时间
They're here, right on schedule.
机棚门 把它打开
The hangar door, open it.
真准时
Clockwork.
天啊! 你把这新闻给我
Jeez, you give me this story,
我就替你生孩子
and I'll have your baby.
我可不想你占便宜
Not the kind of ride I'm looking for.
上校 容我说 你真是了不起的
Colonel, if I may say so, you are some piece of work.
谢谢你 少校
Thank you, Major.
你自己也不错
You're not so bad yourself.
恭喜你逃了出来 长官
Congratulations on your escape, sir.
谢谢你 少校
Thank you, Major.
也许待留到我们安全后再说
Maybe you should save them until we are all safe, hmm?
是 长官
Sir.
我要恭喜各位
My congratulations, gentlemen.
你们赢得了自己的生活方式
You've won a victory for our way of life,
还有我的骄傲 我的钦佩… 和一个绝顶的假期
my pride, my admiration, and a kick...ass vacation.
登机吧!
Now, get on board.
怎么了 牛仔 飞行让你不舒服?
What's the matter, cowboy, ride too rough?
我不喜欢飞行
I don't like to fly.
那你到这上头来干嘛?
Then what are you doing here?
我也不喜欢输
I don't like to lose, either.
好了 我们走吧
O.K. Whoo! Here we go!
我不知道你们怎么想
I don't know about you guys,
我再也不要在雪地里滚了
but I've seen enough fucking snow to last me a lifetime.
温带是不下雪的 少校
You don't get much of that in the tropics, Major.
为了你们 我们可以进口雪
For you, gentlemen, we'll import it.
他妈的! 他们出机棚了
Shit! They left the hangar!
那边
Right there.
那边 拍摄那架747
Right there. Get that.
现在该怎样?
All right, now what?
挡在他们前头
Get in front of them! Take it down!
使他们无法起飞
Block their path so they can't get out of there!
我可不跟那200吨的飞机玩老鹰抓小鸡游戏
I'm not playing chicken with a 200...ton plane!
我虽疯但还没那么疯呢
I'm crazy, man, but I ain't that crazy.
算了吧
Forget it.
达拉斯 我是西北140班机
Dulles, this is Northeast 140.
请求跑道降落
Request clearance on first available runway.
是荷莉的飞机
That's Holly's plane.
重覆 要求紧急降落许可!
Repeat. Request emergency clearance.
我知道你们不能回答
I know you're not going to answer me,
但是最好听清楚
but you damn well better listen!
我们油料用光了 必须降落
We're down to fumes, and we have to land,
五分钟 不管怎样 我们一定得进场
and in five minutes we're coming in one way or another.
该死 那是我老婆的飞机
That's my wife's plane!
快降到它前面!
Take it fucking down!
才不要到那架飞机前面!
I'm not getting in front of that plane!
好吧… 那你能飞到它上头去吗?
All right, how about getting over top of it?
女士们先生们, 我是机长
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the captain.
请各位注意
Your attention.
我们没有选择
We have no choice
必须尝试紧急迫降
but to attempt an emergency landing.
将你的安全带系好 将身体置于所教的
Please fasten your seat belts and assume crash positions
假设坠机姿势
as instructed by your cabin attendants.
我们按紧急程序行动
Let's have the emergency check list.
达拉斯机场附近飞机请注意
Attention all air traffic in Dulles area.
这是西北140班机
This is Northeast 140.
我们正准备紧急降落
We're going to attempt an emergency landing.
请注意
Be advised.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
我不想死 我不想死
I don't want to die. I don't want to die.
把安全带扣好
Just buckle your seat belt.
我很抱歉 真的很抱歉…
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
请向前倾
Lean forward.
天啊…
God!
哦
Oh!
天啊
Oh, God.
你的杖、你的竿、都安慰我
Thy rod and Thy staff they comfort me.
等一下!
Just hang on!
你要做什么?
What are you doing?
你要新闻不是吗?
You wanted a story, didn't you?
别急慢慢来
Nice and easy, boys.
把我放下去
Get me in low!
收到
You got it!
把我放下去
Bring me down!
你会死的!
You'll get yourself killed!
回里面来!
Come back inside!
飞低一点 保持在机翼上方
Bring it in low! Keep over the wing!
再低点
Lower!
啊
Aah!
约翰 你他妈到这机翼上来做什么?
John, what the fuck are you doing out on the wing of this plane?
该死!
Damn!
可恶
Mierda.
出问题了
There's something wrong.
是副翼
The ailerons.
我们没办法起飞了
We can't take off.
他妈的
Hijo de puta.
又是麦克莱
It's McClane again.
那狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
我来对付他
I'll do him.
做得彻底一点
This time do it right.
将军 你把我们载上天就行了
You just get us in the air, General.
你是唯一会开飞机的人
You're the only man who can do it.
别开枪 机翼里满是油料
Don't shoot. That wing is fully fueled.
呀
Ya!
真可惜 麦克莱 我有点喜欢你呢
Too bad, McClane. I kind of liked you!
哇
Whoa!
我已经有够多朋友了
I got enough friends!
(油箱盖)
好吧 麦克莱
O.K., McClane...
压轴好戏上演了
time for the main event!
王八蛋
Motherfucker!
怎么样?
How's it going?
[法语] 一路顺风!
Bon voyage!
落地快乐 混球
Happy landings, asshole!
再见 王八蛋
Yippie...kai...yay, motherfucker.
好了 这回行了
Yeah. All right.
荷莉
Holly!
这就是给你点的降落灯
Here's your fucking landing light!
天啊
Oh, God.
瞧
Look!
好的 我看见了
O.K., I see it! I see it!
他们利用火光当降落灯
They used the fire to see!
They used the fucking fire to see!
他们可以照做 告诉他们吧
They can all do that. Tell them.
他们已经知道了
They already know.
我们看到东北方的降落点了…
We had a visual on Northeastern's landing.
你听
Listen.
我们正以火苗做为导向…
We're following the fire trail in as a guide.
要是他们能 我们也可以
If they can do it, so can we!
喔
Whoo!
可以活着走出去
If any landing you can walk away from
就是成功的降落 太棒了
is a good one, that's great.
跳!
Jump!
我接着你了
I got you!
跳!
Jump!
这就对了 很好
There you go. That's it.
很好
That's it!
荷莉!
Holly!
来 我们接住你了
Come on! We got you!
天啊 宝贝!
Oh, God. Oh, baby.
我以为我永远再也见不到你了
I thought I was never going to see you again.
我也是这么以为
That's what I thought about you.
我好爱你呀!
I love you so much.
我听说恐怖分子到机场来了
They told me there were terrorists at the airport.
对 我也听说了
Yeah. I heard that, too.
天啊 太美了!
God, that's beautiful.
是呀!
Yeah.
对 的确是
Yup, it sure is.
我太爱你了
Oh, I love you so much.
约翰…
Oh,John.
为什么这种事 老发生在我们身上
Why does this keep happening to us?
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
上车吧
Get in the truck!
我们带她离开吧
Let's get her out of here!
谁来帮我 拜托
Somebody help me, please!
甜心 扶我起来 拜托
Oh, honey, help me up here, please.
混蛋!
Asshole!
警官! 来吧 来吧
Hey, Officer! Hey, come on!
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
快上来 尊夫人也上来
Hop on in here! Get your missus in!
你要怎么办呀? 马文
What do you say, Marv?
我才不会去清理这一团乱呢!
I'll be damned if I'm going to clean up this mess!
麦克莱
Hey, McClane!
你在机场前收到这张罚单的?
You get this parking ticket in front of my airport?
没错
Yeah.
管他呢! 是圣诞节
Ah, what the hell. It's Christmas!
走吧 马文!
Take off, Marv!